Tyler Adkins

Email: adkinsty@icloud.com Website: adkinsty.github.io Phone: (517) 927 3467 Address: Ann Arbor, MI

Summary

Cognitive neuroscientist with 6 years of experience designing experiments and analyzing complex datasets.

Skills

Bayesian data analysis, experimental design, mathematical modeling, data visualization, machine learning, simulation, image processing, formal reasoning, scientific writing, public speaking, literature review, teaching

Tools

R, Python, Stan, JavaScript, Git, Bash, AWS, LaTeX, Illustrator, SQL, MATLAB, C++, HTML

Employment

9/2017 – Present University of Michigan Graduate Research Fellow Ann Arbor, MI Designed experiments, processed large and small multi-dimensional datasets, built parametric and nonparametric statistical models, collaborated with teams of scientists on interdisciplinary research projects, reported research findings in reputable journals and conferences, mentored colleagues in data analysis.

1/2018 – 4/2020 University of Michigan Graduate Student Instructor Ann Arbor, MI Created educational materials and assessments for instructors and students in large lecture courses, provided instruction and tutoring to students in multiple discussion sections, graded written assignments and quizzes

9/2015 – 9/2017 University of Michigan Research Assistant Ann Arbor, MI Configured eye-tracking hardware and software, implemented econometric models of decision-making.

Education

9/2017 – Present	University of Michigan	Ph.D. in Psychology	Ann Arbor, MI
1/2015 – 9/2017	University of Michigan	B.A. in Cognitive Science	Ann Arbor, MI

Awards

2021	Swets Award for Psych. Science (\$25k)
2020	NSF RAPID grant (\$200k)
2019	NSF GRFP (honorable mention)
2018	Scholarship in Math. Psych. (\$3k)
2017	Rackham Merit Fellowship (\$100k)
2016	Phi Kappa Phi
2015	Sweeney Merit Scholarship (\$3k)

Service

2021	Departmental Associate
2020	Forum Committee
2020	Admissions Committee
2019	Social Committee
2018	Recruitment Committee

Publications

Adkins and Lee (2021) Neuroimage [DOI]
Adkins, Lewis, and Lee (2021) Psych. Bulletin & Review [DOI]
Adkins, Gary, and Lee (2021) Nature Scientific Reports [DOI]
Anderson, Adkins, and Lee (2020) J. Neurophysiology [DOI]
Fansher, Adkins , and Shah (in press) <i>JEP: Applied</i>
Adkins and Lee (in review) <i>Psych. Bulletin & Review</i> [DOI]
Fansher, Adkins*, et al. (in review) Memory and Cognit. [DOI]
Fansher, Adkins*, et al. (in review) Cognit. Research: P&I [DOI]
Brissenden, Adkins, et al. (in review) JEP: General [DOI]
Lalwani,, Adkins,et al. (in review) Psych. Science [DOI]
Adkins, Zhang, Jonides, and Lee (in prep)
Adkins, Weissman, and Lee (in prep)

^{*}Shared first authorship